<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>inconvergent</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://inconvergent.net</link>
    <atom:link href="https://inconvergent.net/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Volumetric Light</title>
        <description>
          
          Volumetric Light For a while I have been thinking about how to make some kind of volumetric light effect. There are a lot of resources on things like this, but I have avoided doing any research on this on purpose. Figuring out how something works on my own is an...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://inconvergent.net/2021/volumetric-light/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inconvergent.net/2021/volumetric-light/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Future Alterations and Loops</title>
        <description>
          
          Future Alterations and Loops In the previous post i described a feature of my common lisp library. Namely the ability to easily create a graph of future alterations that depend on each other. This is achieved by naming the result of an alteration, and referencing named results inside the same...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://inconvergent.net/2021/future-alterations-and-loops/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inconvergent.net/2021/future-alterations-and-loops/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Future Alterations</title>
        <description>
          
          Future Alterations When I started learning Common Lisp I also started writing a framework for generative art. The first version was named snek. After a large refactoring it was renamed to weir. This is the current version. In this framework drawings are represented as graphs. One of the ideas I...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://inconvergent.net/2020/future-alterations/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inconvergent.net/2020/future-alterations/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Making Money</title>
        <description>
          
          Making Money I wrote a slightly incoherent thread of tweets a little while ago about how I think about making and selling art. And how much money I make from it. Here is a more comprehensive version of the thread. First of all, I consider myself an artist. However, I...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://inconvergent.net/2020/making-money/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inconvergent.net/2020/making-money/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>More Asemic Writing</title>
        <description>
          
          More Asemic Writing I've worked on asemic writing several times. Most recently I described a system based on Bézier curves, which mimics some kind of cursive. After this I started experimenting with a method to to make something that is more akin to systems such as Hangul or Katakana. I...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://inconvergent.net/2020/asemic-writing/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inconvergent.net/2020/asemic-writing/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Depth of Field with Colour Shift</title>
        <description>
          
          Depth of Field with Colour Shift The last time I wrote, I described a relatively easy way to get a nice depth of field effect. Let's see how we can add a colour shift effect as well. I've tried to repeat most of the relevant information here, but you might...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://inconvergent.net/2019/colour-shift/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inconvergent.net/2019/colour-shift/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Depth of Field</title>
        <description>
          
          Depth of Field The 3D webs in the previous post are represented as graphs. Rendering them in 3D presents a few challenges. Depending on what tools you use, you might be able to convert them into meshes. There are several other ways to do it as well. 3D structure rendered...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://inconvergent.net/2019/depth-of-field/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inconvergent.net/2019/depth-of-field/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Tangle of Webs 3D</title>
        <description>
          
          A Tangle of Webs 3D In the previous post I described an algorithm for generating web-like structure in two dimensions. It is possible to extend this to 3D with a few relatively simple changes. When generating the web structure in 2D we use intersections along a line to place new...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://inconvergent.net/2019/a-tangle-of-webs-3d/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inconvergent.net/2019/a-tangle-of-webs-3d/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Tangle of Webs</title>
        <description>
          
          A Tangle of Webs A while ago I started experimenting with an algorithm for creating web-like structures in two dimensions. Arguably the results are a little strange when compared to most spider webs, but interesting nonetheless. The image below is a picture of a plotter drawing made using a variation...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://inconvergent.net/2019/a-tangle-of-webs/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inconvergent.net/2019/a-tangle-of-webs/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Order and Chaos</title>
        <description>
          
          Order and Chaos When experimenting with generative algorithms it is sometimes useful to start with a highly organized structure. Then try to find interesting ways to gradually disrupt it. Obvious starting choices are geometric primitives, but regular grids and other patterns will work too. Interesting generative results can often be...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://inconvergent.net/2018/order-and-chaos/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inconvergent.net/2018/order-and-chaos/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A History</title>
        <description>
          
          A History 2020: noBlockchain is the new database hype. It turns out to be csv files, stored directly on the file system. It is an enormous improvement. 2022: The most used DB is implemented on top of Stuxnet. 2025: Most of the world is covered in used graphics cards. 2027:...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://inconvergent.net/a-history/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inconvergent.net/a-history/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Myriad of Mistakes</title>
        <description>
          
          A Myriad of Mistakes A while ago I wrote about a way to introduce &quot;mistakes&quot; into a generative system, as a way of creating surprising results. Then I did an experiment where I tried to implement this using the same generative techniques I use in a lot of my other...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://inconvergent.net/2018/a-myriad-of-mistakes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inconvergent.net/2018/a-myriad-of-mistakes/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
